# Layla Abo Saad

Phone: +96170605255 Email:<u>Laylaabosaad@gmail.com</u> Location:Beirut-Lebanon Linkedin: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/laylaAboSaad</u> Github: <u>https://github.com/laylaabosaad</u>

#### **Profile**

I am a Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for building creative web applications. I am experienced in popular frameworks and libraries using React JS, Laravel, NodeJs, Wordpress, and more to create dynamic, user-friendly web applications, and deliver projects to a high standard. As an ambitious, hard-working, and a motivated individual, I aim to turn challenging ideas into reality.

### **Experience**

Full Stack Web Developer

Way2Go | June 2023 - Present

A Canadian-based company that offers a full 360-degree Digital Transformation and Marketing Solutions to clients.

- Collaborated with a diverse team to deliver high-quality websites to clients.
- Worked on both back-end and front-end using Laravel and ReactJs respectively.
- Contributed to the optimization and maintenance of existing websites, ensuring smooth performance and enhancing user experience.

Full Stack Web Developer

Codi Tech || November 2022 – June 2023

An intensive boot-camp that aims to prepare students for the latest technology in programming to gain job skills needed in the market. I had the honor to work on several projects in teams that increased my collaboration skills and my leadership abilities.

- Developed various projects using different languages and platforms in the back-end including NodeJS, Express, PHP, Laravel, SQL and MongoDB.
- Worked on several front-end projects by using ReactJS.
- Used WordPress to create several websites including portfolios and e-commerce.
- Applied the AGILE methodology while working with diverse teams.

## Languages

Arabic: Native Speaker | English: Professional Working Level.

## **Projects**

I have worked on several projects that showcase my skills on both front-end and back-end development. The projects involved creating a responsive and user-friendly front-end interface using ReactJS. On the back-end, I designed and implemented a RESTful API using Node.js and MongoDB to handle user authentication and data storage. Additionally, I worked with different team members that increased my teamwork and communication skills. Through these projects, I have gained a strong understanding of web development principles and have honed my abilities to deliver high-quality, scalable, and maintainable code.

- Portfolio for Stone Age Group || WordPress || <a href="https://stoneage.group/">https://stoneage.group/</a> A portfolio is being created using WordPress. The portfolio comprises various sections about the work of Stone Age group and provides viewers with the ability to contact them via email.
- E-commerce website for "Mini-Garden" || MERN Stack || <a href="https://minigarden22a.netlify.app">https://minigarden22a.netlify.app</a>
  This project was implemented using the MERN stack, which includes MongoDB, Express, and NodeJs for the back-end and ReactJS for the front-end. The website aims to enable users to contact the admin and place orders for the products they like.
- E-commerce website for "Vressocasa"|| LAMP Stack || <a href="https://www.vressocasa.com">https://www.vressocasa.com</a>
  The project was implemented in a dynamic team where we used php and Laravel for the back-end, and ReactJS for the front-end. The website consists of different sections that allow users to order products, observe blogs, and decide the type of payment.

#### **Education**

- Master 1 in Applied Animal Sciences | Lebanese University, Faculty of Science | 2020-2022. Graduation project on "Stem Cells Neurotherapy of Traumatic Brain Injury".
- Bachelor degree in Biology | Lebanese University, Faculty of Science | 2017-2020.

#### **Skills**

- Skilled in LAMP stack, MERN stack, and WordPress.
- Flexibility and adaptability in the workplace.
- Strong analytical thinking and attention to details.
- Excellent teamwork, communication, and organization skills.
- Computer literate in standard software applications (Excel, Microsoft office, power point).